Guide to the Terry Sanford Papers, 1926-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Legislative Files Series, 1986-1992
  - Environment Subseries, 1958-1992(bulk 1986-1992)
    - Western North Carolina:
      - Wilderness Act, S. 767, HR.35, 1991-1992 (Box 125)
    - Wetlands, 1988-1992, (3 folders) (Box 125)
    - Wetland policy, 1991-1992 (Box 125)
    - Wildlife:
      - 1986-1992 (Box 125)
      - Fish and Wildlife Enforcement Clarification Act of 1992, 1990-1992 (Box 125)
      - Law Enforcement Bill, 1990-1992 (Box 125)
      - Management, 1991-1992 (Box 125)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1989, (3 folders) (Box 125)
  - Appropriations Subseries, 1986-1992
    Correspondence, staff and committee memoranda, reports, clippings, and other materials pertaining to Senate appropriations bills.
    - Agriculture: (Box 125)
      - Biotechnology, North Carolina, 1988-1991 (Box 125)
      - Rural Development and related agencies:
        - 1988-1992, (4 folders) (Box 125)
        - Bowman Gray Nutrition Center, 1989-1992 (Box 125)
    - Caribbean Basin Initiative, 1989 (Box 125)
    - Central America, 1987-1990 (Box 125)
    - Cherokee Reservation water treatment plant, 1988-1989 (Box 125)
    - Commerce:
      - Haywood County, 1989-1990 (Box 125)
      - Justice, state, and judiciary, 1987-19992, (4 folders) (Box 125)
    - Defense:
      - 1987-1992 (Box 125)
      - Desert Storm, 1991 (Box 125)
    - European development, 1990-1991 (Box 125)
    - Economic Recovery Plan, 1991-1992 (Box 125)
    - Economic Development Administration: University Center Program, 1990-1991 (Box 125)
    - Education: Head Start, 1989-1991 (Box 125)
    - Energy and water: Miscellaneous, 1989-1992, (3 folders) (Box 125)
    - Energy and water: (Box 126)
      - Peninsula Park, 1989-1990 (Box 126)
      - Port of Wilmington, 1989-1990 (Box 126)
    - Environment, pollution and health issues, 1987-1992 (Box 126)
    - Environment Protection Agency: Research Triangle Park facility, 1987-1992 (Box 126)
    - Highway:
      - Bill briefing notebook, 1991 (Box 126)
      - Letters, 1991-1992 (Box 126)
      - Mass transit, 1991 (Box 126)
    - Housing and homelessness, 1990-1991 (Box 126)
    - Hurricane Hugo, 1991 (Box 126)
    - Interior:
      - Conservation, undated (Box 126)
      - Forest service, 1989-1990 (Box 126)
      - Memos, 1990-1991 (Box 126)
      - Parks, 1987-1990 (Box 126)
      - Refuges, 1987-1992, (3 folders) (Box 126)
    - Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, 1987-1991, (2 folders) (Box 126)
    - Legislative branch, 1990-1992 (Box 126)
    - Military, construction, 1990-1992 (Box 126)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 126)
    - Science Foundation facilities, 1991-1992 (Box 126)
    - Small business, 1988-1991 (Box 126)
    - Space Station Freedom, 1987-1992 (Box 126)
    - Superconducting Super Collider, 1987-1992 (Box 126)
    - Taxes, 1989-1992, (2 folders) (Box 126)
    - Treasury, postal service, general government: Grove Arcade Building, Asheville, 1987-1992 (Box 126)
    - Treasury, postal service, general government: Miscellaneous, 1990-1992 (Box 126)
    - Transportation:
      - Bonner Bridge, 1990-1991 (Box 126)
      - Currituck Dare Bridge, 1992 (Box 126)
      - Federal Aviation Administration reauthorization, 1992 (Box 126)
      - Highway N.C. 12 (Outerbanks), 1991-1992 (Box 126)
      - Highways U.S. 23/I-26 corridor, 1988-1992 (Box 126)
      - Lufthansa, 1989-1992 (Box 126)
      - Miscellaneous, 1988-1992, (2 folders) (Box 126)
      - New Bern Bridge, 1992 (Box 126)
    - Veteran's Affairs:
      - Housing and Urban Development: Independent agencies, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 126)
  - Assistants' Files Subseries, 1987-1992
    Primarily memoranda and correspondence of Sanford's legislative assistants, including many letters composed for Sanford. The materials address a broad range of legislative and other issues. Much of the subseries documents the relationships between Sanford's office and various government and private organizations.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject and occasionally by the legislative assistant's last name.
    - A (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - ABM Treaty, 1987 (Box 127)
    - ACDA Authorization Bill, 1987 (Box 127)
    - AIDS: Epidemic prevention: Global, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Amendment 1069: Redefine deficit, undated (Box 127)
    - American Dance Festival, 1988 (Box 127)
    - American School Foundation: Floyd Travis, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Association of American Universities, 1988 (Box 127)
    - Amnesty International USA, undated (Box 127)
    - Applications, 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - Arms sales, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 127)
    - B (General correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - Banking, 1991 (Box 127)
    - Banking issues, 1991 (Box 127)
    - Banks: North Carolina, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Bermuda Tax laws, 1988 (Box 127)
    - BIFAD, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Bipartisan support for Central American Peace, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Blackburn, John, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Boren, Richard, 1988 (Box 127)
    - Bork nomination: Statements by other Senators, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Burlington: Work files, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Burlington Industries: Takeover, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - C (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - CA Con. Res. co-sponsor, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Carolina's Council of Housing, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Center for National Policy, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Clean Water Act, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Commemorative stamp, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Congressional record, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Congressional Quarterly weeklies, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Corporate Takeover and Insider Abuse Reform Act of 1987, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - D (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - Davie, William R.: Stamp, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Democratic fair, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Democrats '90s poll, undated (Box 127)
    - Dodd Bill, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Duke, Anthony Drexel, 1986-1987 (Box 127)
    - Duke University: Soviet/U.S. exchange studies, 1987 (Box 127)
    - E (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 127)
    - Ethics, 1992 (Box 127)
    - F (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 127)
    - Family farms, 1988 (Box 127)
    - Federal Legislation Interest of N.C., undated (Box 127)
    - Foreign assistance: Hunger, 1986 (Box 127)
    - Foreign relations:
      - 1986-1987 (Box 127)
      - Memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 127)
    - Foreign Relations Subcommittee: Terrorism, drugs, etc., 1987 (Box 127)
    - FSLIC amendments, 1989 (Box 127)
    - G (General correspondence), 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - Galvin, John R., 1986 (Box 127)
    - General correspondence (Senator), 1991, (6 folders) (Box 128)
    - Generic congratulations (andldquo;At-a Boyandrdquo;), 1987 (Box 128)
    - Great Smoky Mountains Wilderness Act, 1988 (Box 128)
    - Green, Bill:
      - Memorandums, 1987 (Box 128)
      - Personal, 1989 (Box 128)
    - H (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 128)
    - Helsinki Accord, 1987 (Box 128)
    - H. J. Res. 175: Contra Aid Moratorium, 1987 (Box 128)
    - Hillman, Jennifer, 1991 (Box 128)
    - Hoving Group, 1988 (Box 128)
    - H. R. 27, 1987 (Box 128)
    - H.R. 1777: Foreign Relations Authorization Act, 1987 (Box 128)
    - I (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 128)
    - IEP Human Rights Report, 1988 (Box 128)
    - Immigration, 1989 (Box 128)
    - Interim Secret Clearance, 1987 (Box 128)
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1988 (Box 128)
    - International Center for Development Policy, 1986 (Box 128)
    - Inter-Office memorandums, 1987 (Box 128)
    - Interstate Highway Proposal, 1991-1992 (Box 128)
    - Intro of Moratorium Bill, 1987 (Box 128)
    - Invitations, 1986-1987 (Box 128)
    - J (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 128)
    - Jefferson Awards, 1989 (Box 128)
    - Journal of the Inter-American Foundation, 1987 (Box 128)
    - Judiciary Committee: Thomas Johnson Aircraft, 1987 (Box 128)
    - K (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 128)
    - Krassowka, Wanda, 1987-1988 (Box 128)
    - L (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 128)
    - Larkin, Barbara: Memorandums, 1987 (Box 128)
    - London: Embassy of the U.S., 1987 (Box 128)
    - M (General correspondence), 1987-1989 (Box 128)
    - Marpol Treaty, 1987 (Box 128)
    - Meese report, 1988 (Box 129)
    - Mills Manufacturing Corporation, undated (Box 129)
    - MIGA, 1987 (Box 129)
    - MIGA/Adams-Evans substitute, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Montreal protocol, 1987-1988 (Box 129)
    - Moore, Brian, 1989 (Box 129)
    - Morse, Harold E.: the Learning Channel, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Multilateral Development Bank Human Rights report, undated (Box 129)
    - N (General correspondence), 1987-1988 (Box 129)
    - National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors, 1987 (Box 129)
    - National Democratic Club, 1987 (Box 129)
    - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs, 1987 (Box 129)
    - National Endowment for Democracy, 1985-1986 (Box 129)
    - National Institutes of Health, undated (Box 129)
    - National Women's law Center, 1987 (Box 129)
    - N.C. Center for International Understanding, 1989 (Box 129)
    - N.C. Credit Unions (Box 129)
    - N.C. Democratic Executive Committee, 1987 (Box 129)
    - N.C. Institute of Politics, Inc. ( Walter DeVries), 1987 (Box 129)
    - N.C. Literacy for the 21st Century (Governor's Commission), 1988 (Box 129)
    - N.C. Low Income Housing ( Jennifer Hillman) (Box 129)
    - N.C. Mayors: Meeting with, 1987 (Box 129)
    - N.C. judicial nominees, undated (Box 129)
    - O (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 129)
    - OPIC, 1988 (Box 129)
    - OTA Report on the U.S. Textile and Apparel Industry, 1987 (Box 129)
    - P (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 129)
    - Pay raise, 1991 (Box 129)
    - Peace Corps, undated (Box 129)
    - Pell Senator Claiborne, 1987 (Box 129)
    - P.L. 99-353: Immigrants Day, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Presidential inauguration, 1989 (Box 129)
    - Provisions from S. 766 (Box 129)
    - Public Diplomacy staff, 1988 (Box 129)
    - Q (General correspondence), 1987-1988 (Box 129)
    - R (General correspondence), 1987 (Box 129)
    - Radio Mart Program, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Ransom, Matt, 1988 (Box 129)
    - andldquo;Refugee Reports,andrdquo; 1987 (Box 129)
    - Report of the National Bipartisan Commission on Central America, 1984 (Box 129)
    - Request for oversight Hearing: Burlington takeover, undated (Box 129)
    - Retirement, 1987 (Box 129)
    - RTP Hearing: Restoring America's Competitive Edge, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.2: Senatorial Election Campaign of 1987; Boren, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.42: Senatorial Election Campaign Act of 1987, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.100: Central American Democracy and Development Act, 1991 (Box 129)
    - S.101: Budget, 1990 (Box 129)
    - S.173: Hollings Telephone Manufacturing Bill, 1991 (Box 129)
    - S.464: Asbestos, 1988 (Box 129)
    - S.653(a): Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, 1988 (Box 129)
    - S.790: Banks/Competitive Equality Banking Act, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.825: Housing Bill, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.860: The Stars and Stripes Forever, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.998: Micro-Enterprise Loans for the Poor Act, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.1212: Notch Bill, 1990 (Box 129)
    - S.1264: Hostile Foreign Takeover Moratorium Act, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.1275: Semiconductor technology, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.1282: andldquo;International Terrorism,andrdquo; 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.1342: Rantidine hyudrochloride, undated (Box 129)
    - S.1371: Rural Housing Act, undated (Box 129)
    - S.1625: Judges of the Court of Military Appeals, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.2756: Anti-Apartheid Act Amendments of 1988, 1988 (Box 129)
    - S.Con.Res.24:
      - Additional Cosponsors, undated (Box 129)
      - Sanford statement in support of, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.Con.Res.46: Formosa, 1987 (Box 129)
    - SEC.123 of Tax Reform Act 1986: Scholarships and Fellowships, 1986 (Box 129)
    - SFR Committee: Business Meetings, 1988 (Box 129)
    - SDRC: Trip report on Afghanistan, 1988 (Box 129)
    - S.Res.98: Igor v. Ogurtsov (release from exile), 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.Res.122: child immunization, undated (Box 129)
    - S.Res.190: Bill of Rights Bicentennial Day, 1989 (Box 129)
    - S.J.Res: Raoul Wallenberg Tribute Committee, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.J.Res.26: white House Conference on Library and Information Services, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.J.Res.138, 1987 (Box 129)
    - S.Res: U.S. Assistance to Pakistan, undated (Box 129)
    - Sanford Amendment to Foreign Assistance Automation, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Smoking, 1991 (Box 129)
    - State Department Articles, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Subcommittee on International Economic Policy, Trade, Oceans and Environment: November 12 hearing, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Subcommittee on Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs: Hearing, 1991 (Box 129)
    - Takeover amendments, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Takeover Bill: Co-sponsor, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Takeover moratorium support, 1987 (Box 129)
    - United Nations, 1987 (Box 129)
    - Urging President to lift trade embargo: Nicaragua, 1988 (Box 129)
  - Voting Record Subseries, 1986-1992
    Voting record and related statements by Sanford.
    - Appropriations, 1986-1992, (5 folders) (Box 130)
    - Appropriations votes, 1988 (Box 130)
    - Budget, 1986-1992, (2 folders) (Box 130)
    - Defense, 1986-1992, (3 folders) (Box 130)
    - Education, 1986-1992 (Box 130)
    - Energy, 1986-1992, (2 folders) (Box 130)
    - Ethics, 1986-1992 (Box 130)
    - First term overview, 1992 (Box 130)
    - Legislative activities, 1987-1992, (3 folders) (Box 130)
    - Senate Roll Call votes, 101st Congress, 1st Session, 1989, (3 folders) (Box 130)
    - 101st Congress, 2nd Session, 1990, Jan.-Oct., (3 folders) (Box 131)
    - 102nd Congress, 1st Session, 1991, Jan.-Nov., (4 folders) (Box 131)
    - 102nd Congress, 2nd Session, 1992, Jan.-Oct., (4 folders) (Box 131)
    - Senate Voting Record, 1989-1992 (Box 131)
    - Social Security, 1986-1992 (Box 131)
    - Summary and comparisons, 1987-1992 (Box 131)
    - Taxes, 1986-1992, (2 folders) (Box 131)
    - Trade and textile, 1986-1992, (2 folders) (Box 131)
    - Vote summaries, 1990-1991, (3 folders) (Box 131)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1987-1992
    Reports, testimonies, correspondence, staff memoranda, and other materials pertaining to a broad range of issues.
    - Agriculture: (Box 132)
      - 1986-1992, (7 folders) (Box 132)
      - Witchboard program, 1990-1991 (Box 132)
      - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 132)
    - Amateur Radio Spectrum Act, 1991 (Box 132)
    - Apple prices, 1989 (Box 132)
    - Asbestos, 1988 (Box 132)
    - Asian trade, 1987 (Box 132)
    - Banking, 1991 (Box 132)
    - Bills sponsored by Senator Sanford, 1989 (Box 132)
    - Bills files:
      - Bills co-sponsored, 1991 (Box 132)
      - Campaign finance, 1989 (Box 132)
      - Civil Rights Act, 1990 (Box 132)
      - Customs bills, 1992 (Box 132)
      - Drugs: The Drug Problem in the U.S., 1988 (Box 132)
      - Economic Recovery Bill, 1992 (Box 132)
      - Freedom of Choice Act, 1991-1992 (Box 132)
      - Glaxo (S.1342), 1990, (2 folders) (Box 132)
      - Gray market imports, 1986-1987 (Box 132)
      - Gun control (S.1236), 1990 (Box 132)
      - Health care, 1991, (2 folders) (Box 132)
      - Higher Education Act:
        - Amendment, 1992 (Box 132)
        - Sanford Amendment, 1992 (Box 132)
      - Pork Act: Jackson, Neal, 1989 (Box 132)
      - S.640: Product Liability Fairness Act, 1992 (Box 132)
      - Science and Math Education Improvement Bill, 1989-1992 (Box 132)
      - Smoking Policy, 1991 (Box 132)
      - Social Security Notch Adjustment Act of 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 132)
      - Social Security Trust Funds, 1991 (Box 132)
      - Taxes, 1992 (Box 132)
      - Textile Bill: (Box 133)
      - 1987 (Box 133)
      - S. 2411, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 133)
      - Testimony and statements, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 133)
      - Statements, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 133)
    - Biodiversity, 1987-1990 (Box 133)
    - Black farm ownership, 1987 (Box 133)
    - Black males, 1990-1991, (10 folders) (Box 133)
    - Bowman Gray Nutrition Center, 1990 (Box 133)
    - Burma, 1990 (Box 133)
    - Cable Television Consumer Protection Act, 1991-1992 (Box 133)
    - Campaign Finance Reform, 1989-1992, (3 folders) (Box 133)
    - Campaign Finance Reform, 1991 (Box 134)
    - Canada:
      - Duty remission, 1988 (Box 134)
      - Free Trade Agreement, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 134)
      - Softwood Lumber, 1991, Sept. (Box 134)
      - Trade Mission, 1988, Feb.-Sept. (Box 134)
    - Capel Textile, 1987, July-Sept. (Box 134)
    - Caribbean Basin Initiative, 1988,Apr.- 1990, Feb. (Box 134)
    - Central America:
      - 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 134)
      - Wilson, George (Box 134)
    - Centralized Examination System: Customs, 1987 (Box 134)
    - Ceramic tile: Brazil, 1987 (Box 134)
    - China:
      - 1987-1991 (Box 134)
      - Most favored nation status, 1987, June-1991, July (Box 134)
      - U.S. Symposium on Financial Market, 1986, Nov. (Box 134)
    - Clean Water Act, 1987 (Box 134)
    - Coastal Barrier Resources Act, 1987-1990 (Box 134)
    - Coastal Issues, 1989-1990 (Box 134)
    - Commercial Fisheries, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 134)
    - Co-Sponsorship of bills, 1989-1991 (Box 134)
    - Competitive: Reports, 1989 (Box 134)
    - Community colleges, 1989 (Box 134)
    - Connex pipe, 1990, Sept.-Nov. (Box 134)
    - Congressional Fellows, 1991-1992 (Box 134)
    - Crime Bills, 1989-1992, (2 folders) (Box 134)
    - Diary, 1991 (Box 134)
    - Debt: Equity Swap Legislation, 1987 (Box 134)
    - Eastern Europe: Trade, 1990, Feb.-May (Box 134)
    - Elephants, 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Endangered species, 1987-1990, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Environment:
      - 1987-1991 (Box 135)
      - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Environmentally sustainable development, 1987-1988 (Box 135)
    - EPA, 1988-1989 (Box 135)
    - Exports:
      - Administration Act Amendments, 1990 (Box 135)
      - Bill text, 1990 (Box 135)
      - Industry, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 135)
      - Issues, 1990 (Box 135)
      - Miscellaneous, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Export financing, undated, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Export promotion fees, 1987 (Box 135)
    - Export trading companies, 1987 (Box 135)
    - European Community, 1992 (Box 135)
    - Farm Aid, 1988 (Box 135)
    - Farm Bill, 1990 (Box 135)
    - Farm credit, 1987-1988 (Box 135)
    - Farmworkers, 1988 (Box 135)
    - Federal Prison Industry Competition in Contracting Act, 1990-1991 (Box 135)
    - Fisheries, 1992 (Box 135)
    - Flag burning, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Foreign investment, 1989-1990 (Box 135)
    - FMC: Bolivia project, 1990 (Box 136)
    - Furniture import, 1985-1987 (Box 136)
    - Global warming, 1988-1990 (Box 136)
    - Ground water, 1989-1990 (Box 136)
    - Gun control: Brady Bill, 1991 (Box 136)
    - Hazardous materials and waste, 1989-1990 (Box 136)
    - Hazardous waste: EPA vs. N.C., 1987-1989 (Box 136)
    - Head Start, 1990 (Box 136)
    - Health Care, 1988-1991 (Box 136)
    - Highway Bill, 1987-1992 (Box 136)
    - Historically Black Colleges, 1989-1991 (Box 136)
    - Honoraria Ban for Federal employees, 1991-1992 (Box 136)
    - Hunter protection, 1991 (Box 136)
    - Indian affairs, 1990-1991 (Box 136)
    - International conferences on the environment, 1988-1990 (Box 136)
    - International trade, 1989-1992 (Box 136)
    - Lake Gaston, 1988-1992 (Box 136)
    - Log Export Amendment, 1990 (Box 136)
    - Lumbees, 1988-1992, (12 folders) (Box 136)
    - Lumbee Recognition Bill, 1991-1992 (Box 136)
    - Marine issues, 1987-1988 (Box 136)
    - Marine research, 1989-1900, (2 folders) (Box 137)
    - Military: Miscellaneous, 1987-1991 (Box 137)
    - Multilateral Development Banks, 1987-1988 (Box 137)
    - National teaching standards, 1989 (Box 137)
    - National Ocean Policy, 1987 (Box 137)
    - Nolichucky: Wild/Sanic River designation, 1992 (Box 137)
    - Peanuts, 1991 (Box 137)
    - Price fixing:
      - Letters and statements to Sanford, 1988-1991, (2 folders) (Box 137)
      - Sanford memos, notes, etc, 1987-1991 (Box 137)
      - Senate correspondence and testimonies, 1988-1991 (Box 137)
    - Product Liability Fairness Act, 1989-1991 (Box 137)
    - Product Reform Act, 1989-1990 (Box 137)
    - PVO, 1987-1988 (Box 137)
    - Rural economy, 1992 (Box 137)
    - Rural telephone, 1989 (Box 137)
    - Self-Reliance loans, 1992 (Box 137)
    - Science:
      - Correspondence, 1990, (6 folders) (Box 137)
      - Higher Education Colloquium on Science Facilities, 1990 (Box 137)
      - Technology Policy, 1990 (Box 137)
    - Science: Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 138)
    - Staff Project Files:
      - Education project, 1991 (Box 138)
      - National Forum on Public Service: 1990, (2 folders) (Box 138)
      - Acceptance letters, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Lists, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Logistics, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Letter to participants, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Letters from presidents and chairs, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Staff, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Student evaluations, 1990 (Box 138)
      - Student groups, 1990 (Box 138)
    - Sugar Drawback Amendment, undated (Box 138)
    - Tariff Bills, undated (Box 138)
    - Telecommunications:
      - Equipment, 1991 (Box 138)
      - Regulations, 1989-1991 (Box 138)
    - Textile, Apparel and Footwear Trade Act, 1987-1990 (Box 138)
    - Tobacco:
      - 1987-1991, (2 folders) (Box 138)
      - Advertising, 1986-1992 (Box 138)
      - International Trade, 1986-1990 (Box 138)
      - Smoking, 1991 (Box 138)
      - Miscellaneous, 1987-1991 (Box 138)
    - Trade, 1987-1991 (Box 138)
    - Trade Association: Position papers, undated (Box 138)
    - Trade Bill Conference, undated, (2 folders) (Box 138)
    - Trade and Competitiveness Act, 1988 (Box 138)
    - Transportation:
      - Air, 1987-1990
        - Air Cargo Complex, 1991 (Box 138)
        - Eastern Air Lines, 1989 (Box 138)
        - Air Cargo: North Carolina, 1992 (Box 138)
        - General aviation, 1991 (Box 139)
        - London Route, 1991 (Box 139)
        - Pan Am 103, 1989 (Box 139)
        - Montreal protocol, 1991 (Box 139)
    - Aviation noise: Raleigh-Durham Airport, 1990-1992 (Box 139)
    - Budget, 1991 (Box 139)
    - Highway safety, 1987-1991 (Box 139)
    - Highway Trust Fund, 1986-1990 (Box 139)
    - Hickory flight Service Station, 1990-1991 (Box 139)
    - Lufthansa operations in Charlotte, 1992 (Box 139)
    - Mass Transit, 1991 (Box 139)
    - North Carolina:
      - Air, 1989-1990, (3 folders) (Box 139)
      - Light Rail, 1990-1991 (Box 139)
      - Railroads, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 139)
      - Trucks, 1991 (Box 139)
    - U.S. Air, 1992 (Box 139)
    - United Nations Environment Programme, 1988 (Box 139)
    - United States:
      - Canada Free Trade: Financial Services, 1988, Feb. -Aug. (Box 139)
      - Competitiveness, undated, (2 folders) (Box 139)
      - USSR World Ocean Agreement, 1987-1990 (Box 139)
    - U.S.S. Asheville, 1991 (Box 139)
    - Violent Crime Control Act, 1991 (Box 139)
    - Voting Rights and Registration, 1991-1992 (Box 139)
    - Water projects, 1989-1990 (Box 139)
    - Welfare Act S.2303, 1992 (Box 139)
- Miscellaneous, 1987-1992
  Correspondence, staff memoranda, conference proceedings, and other materials pertaining to Sanford and his activities.
  - Correspondence: (Box 140A)
    - 1989-1991(VIP), (8 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Budget, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Dear Colleague:
      - Letters received, 1988-1990 (Box 140A)
      - Letters sent, 1990 (Box 140A)
  - Education seminars:
    - Advice to President, 1989 (Box 140A)
    - Correspondence from Sanford, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 140A)
    - Federal assistance, 1991 (Box 140A)